Guide to the Jean Toomer Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
The Poetry subseries follows in boxes 55-56. It contains drafts of Toomer's poems, one large collection called "The Wayward and the Seeking," a printed 1938 Christmas greeting (Box 56, folder 1285), and a few magazines of published poems. Only one quarter of the poems contained in "The Wayward and the Seeking" appear elsewhere in the subseries. In the early 1930s, Toomer planned to write another collection of poetry and prose called "Navarin." Only the preface is found with the papers (Box 56, folder 1287). A part of "Blue Meridian," probably Toomer's best-known poem, was published in the winter 1932 issue of Pagany as "Brown River Smile." In 1936 Paul Rosenfeld included the entire manuscript in the last American Caravan. Various drafts of the poem and notes for a prospective collection entitled "The Blue Meridian and Other Poems" can also be found in Box 55, folders 1264-65. Tables of contents for other planned collections have been placed at the beginning of the subseries in a folder of notes (Box 55, folder 1260) and unidentified drafts of poems are filed at the end (Box 56, folder 1309).
Reviews (Box 57), the sixth subseries, contains Toomer's reviews of books and plays, including The Vegetable by F. Scott Fitzgerald. It reflects Toomer's early interest in such writers as D. H. Lawrence, Lola Ridge, and Zona Gale and his collaboration with Paul Rosenfeld, Waldo Frank, and Gorham Munson. Toomer's review of Munson's book Waldo Frank: A Study, for example, is corrected in Munson's hand (Box 57, folder 1327). In the 1940s and 1950s, his taste changed to more religious authors, such as Gerald Heard and the writings of psychotherapists like John G. McKenzie.
The Writings series ends with three boxes of Short Stories. They include early drafts of "Avey," "Bona and Paul," and "Rhobert" and printed versions of "Fern," "Karintha," and "Kabnis," all of which were published in Cane. "Withered Skin of Berries," written in the same style as Cane, is found in Box 59, folder 1397. During his Chicago period, Toomer combined his early lyricism and Gurdjieffian thought to produce two collections of short stories: "Lost and Dominant" and "Winter on Earth and Short Stories." Three unidentified stories about Old Moses (a Negro farmer), New York City, and Martin Jones, the Mad King from Seattle, are filed at the end of the subseries (Box 59, folder 1398-99).
The Family Papers series contains over six boxes of Jean Toomer's personal papers, nearly two boxes of Margery Latimer Toomer's writings, and two folders of Bismark Pinchback's journals and poems. Uncle Bismark, who studied medicine briefly at Yale and later graduated from Howard University, first stimulated Toomer's interest in literature and art. A journal Bismark wrote in his early thirties containing "essays, letters, dreams, verse, and short stories" as well as a few loose poems comprise his personal papers found with the collection.
Approximately two-thirds of the Jean Toomer subseries consists of his journals. Those from 1920-26 contain notes on his reading of poetry (Box 60, folder 1411), P. D. Ouspensky (Box 60, folder 1412), and Herman Melville (Box 60, folder 1417); notes on friends, such as Hart Crane (Box 60, folder 1415), Georgia O'Keeffe, and Alfred Stieglitz (Box 60, folders 1413-14); and the result of the Gurdjieff work (Box 60, folder 1416).
Notebooks that do not relate to a specific writing were placed with Toomer's journals; however, a few have notes for books. His "autobiography" notebook (Box 61, folder 1420), for example, contains notes for "Transatlantic" and "Earth Being." His "Paris" notebook from the same 1929-30 period also considers the problems of an interracial marriage with Emily Otis (Box 61, folder 1419).
From 1935-41 Toomer faithfully recorded his daily thoughts, most of which are incorporated into journal-like books such as "Psychologic Papers." The rest are filed with his journals, including notes for a book called "The Self Behind Me" (Box 61, folder 1422) and a "psychological diary" for April-May 1938 (Box 61, folders 1427-32). There is also a notebook about his trip to India in 1939 (Box 62, folder 1435) and a few dated prayers from 1946-47 (Box 62, folder 1441).
In 1949 Toomer began Jungian analysis. Notes about his dreams and daily events, including the death of Gurdjieff, are filed with his journals from 1949-50 (Boxes 62-63, folders 1442-55). In the fall of 1950 he began studying dianetics. Four of his dianetic notebooks, in which he "audited" participants (Box 63, folders 1456-59), and seven case books (Box 64, folders 1461-67) are found with his journals. Toomer's journals also include notes on his physical condition from 1951-52 (Box 64, folders 1460 and 1468).
From 1953-54, Toomer attended Gurdjieff group meetings in New York. Many of his loose journal notes from these years are about these meetings, as well as the relaxation techniques he learned from John G. Bennett.
Some of his undated journals contain notes about New Mexico (Box 65, folder 1482), additional reading lists (Box 65, folder 1483), ideas for short stories (Box 64, folder 1480), and a list of the important men and women in his life (Box 64, folder 1479).
The rest of Jean Toomer's personal papers are arranged alphabetically by type of material or subject. School papers (Boxes 65-66, folders 1498-1504), a college scrapbook (Box 66, folder 1505), and a 1917 yearbook (Box 66, folder 1510) concern Toomer's formative years. Newspaper clippings discuss his literary career and marriage to Margery Latimer. There is also a folder of clippings about Toomer's friend Charles Dupee, whose wife filed for divorce after Dupee's participation in the Portage experiment (Box 60, folder 1406). A chalk drawing of Toomer as the Black Prince (Box 74, folder 1643), his 1924 membership certificate in the Institute for the Harmonious Development of Man (Box 60, folder 1404), an agreement to practice as a dianetics auditor (Box 65, folder 1485), and four folders of photographs complete the subseries.
The Margery Latimer Toomer subseries of Family Papers contains primarily drafts and printed versions of her short stories, as well as a few photographs, newspaper clippings concerning her writings and tragic death, and a journal in which she mentions Katherine Mansfield, A. R. Orage, and Waldo Frank. In "The Ship," a story about the Portage experiment, Margery characterizes Jean as Chief Officer Navigass. Untitled drafts and unidentified fragments are filed at the end. The piece which begins, "Live in my body, O my town and my people!" is about her "perfect marriage" to Jean Toomer (Box 67, folder 1535).
The Related Papers series (Boxes 68-70) contains nearly two boxes of papers generated by Georges Gurdjieff, reports and publications of the Society of Friends that do not belong elsewhere, a box of Subject Files containing newspaper articles divided into ten subjects, and Writings of Others. The Gurdjieff material includes transcripts of some of his lectures from 1921-44, typed drafts from his book Beelzebub's Tales to His Grandson, including Toomer's notes (Box 68, folder 1551), a scenario for a ballet (Box 69, folder 1564), reviews of his other writings, Toomer's compilation of Gurdjieff's sayings (Box 68, folder 1546), and a pamphlet on the Institute for the Harmonious Development of Man. Also included are papers from three of Gurdjieff's disciples: John G. Bennett, A. R. Orage, and Toomer. Toomer's folder contains organizational information, such as membership lists of his groups in New York and Chicago.
The Society of Friends subseries contains odd issues of the Friends Intelligencer; pamphlets by Douglas V. Steere, Howard E. Collier, and others; and articles about Friends in Time and in Philadelphia newspapers. It also contains reports, newsletters, and articles on military training, peace, and nonviolence (Box 69, folder 1574).
The Subject Files reflect Toomer's lifelong interests in art and architecture, education, India, New Mexico, psychology and religion, science, social history, and World War II. A folder on literature primarily contains reviews of books by contemporary authors. Another on race relations contains articles on Jews as well as Negroes.
The last subseries, Writings of Others, contains manuscripts of literary friends like Hart Crane and Mabel Dodge Luhan, the writing assignments of students such as Caroline M. Bliss and Nadja Williams, newsletters from his Gurdjieff disciple, Jeremy Lane, and fiction by other friends including Fritz Peters. Interfiled with Morris's typescript on numerology is Toomer's analysis of his family and friends (Box 70, folder 1598).
Printed Works, the final series, contains miscellaneous issues of magazines, books, pamphlets, and newsletters collected by Toomer. They cover topics ranging from raising pigeons to baseball. Publications include a pamphlet about Edgar Cayce and a brochure on the Walden School in New York, which was founded by Margaret Naumburg. Two printed works are inscribed to Margery Latimer or Jean Toomer by their authors: From Negro to Caucasin by Louis Baldwin and Black Man and White Ladyship by Nancy Cunard. The rest of the material is arranged alphabetically by author or title in Boxes 71-72.
African American authors; African Americans in literature; American literature -- African American authors; Art; Authors, American; Communication in marriage; Dianetics; Dreams; Education; Interracial marriage; Psychoanalysis; Psychological literature; Psychology and religion; Race relations; Religious literature; Social history -- 20th Century; Society of Friends; Spiritualism; Streets -- Pennsylvania -- Doylestown; World War, 1939-1945; India -- Description and travel; New Mexico -- Social life and customs; Autobiographies (documents); Diaries; Drawings (visual works); Photographs; Authors; Spiritualists; Anderson, Sherwood, 1876-1941; Baldwin, Louis Fremont; Bennett, John G. (John Godolphin), 1897-1974; Bliss, Caroline Mirza; Bunnell, Elise; Burke, Kenneth, 1897-1993; Campbell, Berta Ochsner; Cane, Melville, 1879-1980; Cayce, Edgar, 1877-1945; Content, Harry, -1941; Content, Marjorie, 1895-1984; Crane, Hart, 1899-1932; Cunard, Nancy, 1896-1965; Derleth, August, 1909-1971; Dupee, Charles; Dupee, Gordon; Dupee, Katharine Green; Dupee, Yvonne; Exman, Eugene; Fauset, Jessie Redmon, 1882-1961; Frank, Waldo David, 1889-1967; Goldman, Perry M.; Goldsmith, Lide; Green, Mildred O.; Greene, Felix; Grove, Max; Grove, Shirley; Gurdjieff, Georges Ivanovitch, 1872-1949; Hergenham, Mildred; Hood, Evelyn; Hubben, William, 1895-1974; Jones, Rachel Latimer; Kelm, Karlton, 1908-1987; Kelm, William; Lane, Betty; Lane, Jeremy; Latimer, Clark Watt; Latimer, Laurie Bodine; Latimer, Margery, 1899-1932; Schubart, Dorothy Obermeyer; Smith, Harrison; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946; Toomer, Jean, 1894-1967; Toomer, Nathan; Toomer, Nina Pinchback; Turbyfill, Mark, 1896-1990; Walcott, Eugenia B.; Walcott, Russell S.; Walker, Dorothy; Ware, Ruth; Wright, Mae; Toomer family
- Correspondence, 1918-63; Series I; 4.25; (10 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Boxes 1-10 hold Series I, Correspondence, which is divided into the correspondence of Jean Toomer and Margery Latimer Toomer. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent then chronologically. Most of Jean Toomer's correspondents with less than five letters have been placed in "letter" general files. Separate listings have been given, however, for each correspondent of Margery Latimer Toomer. Jean Toomer's unidentified correspondence is arranged by first name in Box 9, folders 286-90, followed by two folders of unidentified letters and envelopes. Box 10, folder 342 contains unidentified letters to Margery Latimer Toomer.
  - JEAN TOOMER
    - "A" general, 1923-51 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Adelphi, 1931-39 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alfred A. Knopf, 1930-31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The American Caravan
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Box 7, folder 220
    - The American Dramatists, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Anderson, Paul
      See: Box 3, folder 96
    - Anderson, Sherwood, 1922-34 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The Associated Negro Press
      See: Box 1, folder 10
    - Association for Research and Enlightenment
      See: Box 1, folder 29
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1928-34 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "B" general, 1923-54 (Box 1, Folder 7-9)
    - Barnett, Claude A., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Barton, Betsey, 1941-47 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Beardsley, Josephine, 1930 Oct-Nov (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bennett, John G., 1953-54 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bifur, 1929 Feb-Nov (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bliss, Caroline Mirza, 1930-34 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Boni & Liveright, Inc., 1921-33 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      See also: Box 26, folder 610
    - The Bookman, 1928-31 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Brinton, Howard H. & Anne Cox
      See: Box 7, folders 233-42
    - Broom, 1920-23, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Brownell, Baker, 1927-29 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bunnell, Elise, 1928-32 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Burdick, Adelaide, 1934 Jan-Apr (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Burke, Kenneth
      See: Box 2, folder 45
    - Burrill, Mary, 1932, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "C" general, 1923-50 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
    - Campbell, Berta Ochsner, 1927-34, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Campbell, Douglas, 1929-34 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Cane, Melville & Florence, 1924-32 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Carter, Mary Duncan, 1928-30 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Cayce, Edgar, 1943-44 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Chambers, John
      See: Box 3, folder 98
    - Chambrun, Jacques, 1932-33 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1931-34 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Chase, Laura Greshemer, 1932-39 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Collins, Seward
      See: Box 1, folder 17
    - Committee for the Release of Jacques Roumain, 1935-36 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Content, Harry, 1934-39 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Content, Marjorie
      See: Marjorie Content Toomer, Box 8, folder 251
    - Coward-McCann, Inc., 1928-30 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Crane, Hart, 1923-24 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - The Crisis, 1922-32 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Cullen, Countee P., 1923 Jun-Sep (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "D" general, 1931-55 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - D. Appleton-Century Company, Inc., 1946 Apr-Oct (Box 1, Folder 40)
      See also: Box 4, folders 148-49
    - Damuth, Libbie, 1931-34 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Davenport, Elsa, 1935-42 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Davenport, Franklin, 1939-40 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - de Hartmann, Olga
    - de Salzmann, Madame Jeanne, 1953-54 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - The Dial, 1922-35 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - The Double Dealer, 1922-24 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Doubleday & Company, 1930-48 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Doylestown Chamber of Commerce, 1939 Jan 7 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      See also: Box 46, folder 950
    - Doylestown Daily Intelligencer, 1955 Feb-Apr (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Drachman, Daniel C., 1929 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Du Bois, W. E. B.
      See: Box 1, folder 37
    - The Dubuque Dial, 1934-35 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Dupee, Charles, 1928-45 (Box 2, Folder 52-60)
    - Dupee, Gordon, 1934-40 (Box 2, Folder 61-62)
    - Dupee, Helen, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Dupee, Katherine Green ("Tockie"), 1931-46 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Dupee, Pauline, 1931-58, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Dupee, Yvonne, 1927-38, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 66-75)
    - "E" general, 1922-51 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - E. P. Dutton & Co., Inc., 1937-44 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Exman, Eugene
    - "F" general, 1930-49 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Fadiman, Clifton P.
      See: Box 7, folder 231
    - Fauset, Jessie Redmon
    - Fitts, Norman, 1922-23 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Flinn, Katherine ("Carey"), 1926-27 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - The Forum, 1929-30 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Frances Spencer Real Estate, 1935 Nov (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Frank, Nino
      See: Box 1, folder 14
    - Frank, Waldo, 1920-24 (Box 3, Folder 83-85)
    - Friends Intelligencer, 1941-47 (Box 3, Folder 86)
      See also: Society of Friends, Box 7, folder 233
    - "G" general, 1924-52 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Gale, Zona, 1931-34 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Goldsmith, Lide, 1923-34 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Green, Katherine
      See: Katherine Green Dupee, Box 2, folder 64
    - Green, Mildred O., 1930-34 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Greene, Felix, 1941-45 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Gregary, Miles & Roma, 1931-34 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Grove, Max, 1930-58 (Box 3, Folder 93-94)
    - Grove, Shirley, 1931-40 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Gurdjieff, Georges Ivanovich, 1926-49, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 96)
      See also: Box 5, folder 173
    - "H" general, 1923-49 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Hallowell, Marguerite
    - Harper & Brothers, 1928-48 (Box 3, Folder 98-100)
    - Harrison Smith and Robert Haas, Inc.
      See: Box 7, folder 232
    - Heard, Gerald, 1938-41 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Henry Holt and Company
      See: Box 4, folders 148-49
    - Herndon, Angelo, 1937-38 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Hood, Evelyn, 1931-34, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 103-06)
    - The Hound & Horn, 1929-30 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - [Howarth], Jessmin, 1931-32, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Hubbard Foundation, 1950-52 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Hubben, William
      See: Box 3, folder 86
    - Huebert, Diana, 1931-34 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Huxley, Aldous, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - "I" general, 1952, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Inglis, Hugh, 1939-41 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - "J" general, 1922-46 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - J. H. Sears Company, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Jackson May Howard, 1923-24 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - The John Day Company, Inc.
      See: Box 8, folder 278
    - Johnson, Georgia Douglas, 1928-41 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Johnson, James Weldon, 1930 Jul (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Johnson, Kitty, 1923-24 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Jones, Rachel Latimer & family, 1932-48 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Jones, Rufus M., 1938-47 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Josephson, Matthew
      See: Box 1, folder 18
    - "K" general, 1930-48 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Kelm, Karlton & William
      See: Box 2, folder 51
    - Kitchen, Paul, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Kite, Florence
      See: Box 7, folder 233-42
    - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1935, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - "L" general, 1922-45 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - La Follette, Miss
      See: Box 9, folder 281
    - The Lakeside Press
      See: Box 7, folder 217
    - Lane, Betty, 1931-35 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Lane, Jeremy, 1927-34 (Box 4, Folder 128-29)
    - Latimer, Clark Watt, 1930-34, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 130-33)
    - Latimer, Laurie Bodine, 1932-47 (Box 4, Folder 134-37)
    - Latimer, Margery
      See: Margery Latimer Toomer, Box 8, folder 250
    - Latimer, Rachel
      See: Rachel Latimer Jones, Box 4, folder 121
    - Leighton, Fred, 1928-57 (Box 4, Folder 138-41)
    - Leighton, Lucy Ann, 1931-34 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - LeSueur, Meridel, 1932-33 (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Leverett, Blanche, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - The Liberator, 1921-22 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Liberty Music Shop, 1942-43 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - Lieber, Maxim, 1933-36 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Lightship, Frederick W.
    - Lindley, Denver, 1944-47 (Box 4, Folder 148-49)
    - The Little Review, 1922-26 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Liveright, Horace B.
      See: Box 1, folder 16
    - Locke, Alain LeRoy, 1922-23, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Loeb, James, 1937-46, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 152-54)
    - Loeb, Susan, 1934 Jan-Jul (Box 5, Folder 155)
    - Long, Haniel, 1937-41 (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - Longmans, Green & Co., Inc., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1925-34, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 158-59)
    - "M" general, 1923-47 (Box 5, Folder 160-61)
    - McClure, John
      See: Box 2, folder 46
    - McCormack, Jeanne and Tom, 1957-58 (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - McCormick, Charles G., 1946-48 (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Macgowan, Kenneth, 1923-24 (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - McIntosh & Otis, Inc., 1931-34 (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - McLure, Clare Edgar, 1927-34, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 166-69)
    - The Macmillan Company, 1930-37, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Matthias, Blanche C., 1923-33, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Melquist, Jerome, 1947 Feb-Mar (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Metz, Bernard, 1929-55 (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Meyers, Bay, 1929-31 (Box 5, Folder 174-76)
    - Miller, Richmond P.
    - Minne, Eleanor, 1923-24 (Box 5, Folder 177)
    - Mitchell, Maxine, 1931-34 (Box 5, Folder 178)
    - Modern Review, 1922-24 (Box 5, Folder 179)
    - Moore, Marianne
    - Moorland, Jesse E., 1922 Jul-Dec (Box 5, Folder 180)
    - Morgan, Parker
      See: Box 4, folder 109
    - Morgan, S. Rowland, 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Morris, Alberta
    - [Mortimer], Nadja, 1931-34 (Box 5, Folder 182)
      See also: Box 70, folder 1601
    - Munson, Gorham B., 1922-47, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 183-90)
    - "N" general, 1920-50 (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1923-35 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Naumburg, Margaret, 1922-33, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 193-97)
    - The New Caravan
    - New Democracy, Inc., 1937 Apr (Box 6, Folder 198)
    - The New Republic, 1923-34, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - The Nomad
      See: Box 7, folder 221
    - Norman, Dorothy, 1934-47 (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - North, Dorothy, 1931-35 (Box 6, Folder 201)
    - "O" general, 1930-63 (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - O'Brien, Edward J., 1923 (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1933-45 (Box 6, Folder 204)
    - Ochsner, Berta
      See: Berta Ochsner Campbell, Box 1, folder 25
    - Orage, A. R., 1924-32 (Box 6, Folder 205-06)
    - Otis, Emily H. & family, 1930-32 (Box 6, Folder 207)
    - Otis, Raymond, 1931-34 (Box 6, Folder 208)
    - "P" general, 1923-50 (Box 6, Folder 209-10)
    - Pentland, Henry John Sinclair, 2d baron
    - Peters, Fritz, 1931-33 (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - Peterson, Dorothy, 1926-34 (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - Pickens, William
      See: Box 6, folder 192
    - Pinchback, Bismark Robert Pinchback, Nettie, 1922-44, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - Pinchback, Nina Hethorn, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - Pinchback, Walter A., 1929-32 (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - Purdy, Theodore M.
      See: Box 1, folder 40
    - Pyle, Robert
    - "R" general, 1930-48 (Box 7, Folder 216)
    - R. R. Donnelley & Sons Company, 1931-32 (Box 7, Folder 217)
      See also: Box 31, folder 698
    - Rees, Richard
      See: Box 1, folder 2
    - Remszhardt, Godo, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 218)
    - Reynolds, Frank
      See: Box 2, folder 48
    - Ridge, Lola
    - Roberts, Sara ("Ted"), 1932-53 (Box 7, Folder 219)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1924-41 (Box 7, Folder 220)
    - Rosenthal, Albert, 1922-24 (Box 7, Folder 221)
    - Ruble, Harriet and Jo, 1922-34 (Box 7, Folder 222)
    - "S" general, 1923-63 (Box 7, Folder 223-24)
    - S4N
      See: Box 3, folder 79
    - Schorer, Mark, 1928-34 (Box 7, Folder 225)
    - Schubart, William Howard & Dorothy, 1932-50 (Box 7, Folder 226)
    - Scott Radio Labs, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 227)
    - Scribner's Magazine
      See: Box 1, folder 31
    - Seligmann, Herbert J., 1940-48 (Box 7, Folder 228)
    - Shire, Mildred, 1930-33 (Box 7, Folder 229)
    - Simon, E. Martia, 1932-33 (Box 7, Folder 230)
    - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1931-32 (Box 7, Folder 231)
    - Smith, Harrison, 1923-34 (Box 7, Folder 232)
    - Society of Friends, 1939-58, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 233-42)
    - Steere, Douglas V.
    - Stieglitz, Alfred, 1923-44 (Box 7, Folder 243)
    - Swayne, Amelia W.
    - "T" general, 1921-45 (Box 8, Folder 244)
    - Tate, Allen, 1923-46 (Box 8, Folder 245)
    - Taylor, Edith, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 246)
    - Taylor, Paul ("Polo"), 1942-55 (Box 8, Folder 247)
    - Taylor, Zella, 1930-33 (Box 8, Folder 248)
    - Theatre Arts Magazine